Software engineer with seven years of experience in developing full-stack applications. Proficient in on-site, distributed team, and contractor environments. Demonstrated ability to lead projects from UX/UI design through system architecture to deployment. Team player with strong verbal and written communication skills.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer, Freelance

04/2022 - Present

Build applications and softwares for various clients (data visualization interfaces, trading tools/applications, e-commerce websites, networking platforms). JavaScript/TypeScript, React/React Native, Node, Python, NextJS, Postgres; Shopify, Google, Stripe APIs

# Software Engineer/Product Manager, Maximus | Xyla 2020-2022

- Used React, TypeScript, Node, Python, Django to build a platform hosting Al-enhanced content. Created data visualization web applications for traders. R/Shiny; Quantmod; Yahoo, Tiingo APIs; Google Cloud Platform
- Collaborated with ML engineers to build a service (Xyla) processing medical LLM and generating scientific articles. React, Django, Python, Postgres, Redis
- Product Manager at UHDArchive, a Maximus/IMAX joint venture: collaborated with ML engineers/Al researchers, supervised beta testing, lead market research, created price model, responsible for finding content producers and archive owners.

# Tutor, Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp | 2U, NY 2019-2021

Supported students through in-person and remote tutoring, graded assignments, supervised projects. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery, Node, MySQL, basics of Python

# Software Engineer, Freelance | ICI, NY

2017-2020

- Contract with Independent Curators International: fixed submissions issues, geolocation, updated and maintained content, created donation interface. HTML, CSS, jQuery, PHP
- Created full-stack web applications using RESTful architecture and user inheritance models, authentication, databases, and unit testing.
   Independent projects:

#### Shift

- built an application for restaurant workers facilitating shift exchange and reducing scheduling time and labor management by 30%.
- designed UX/UI, created a custom calendar and instant notifications.
- implemented back end (data modeling, authentication).

HTML, CSS, React/Redux, MongoDB, Node, Express, JSON Web Tokens, Pusher <u>Central</u>

- created a real-time platform enabling professionals to monitor activity and income from one place and reduce administrative time.
- designed UI/UX, implemented instant messages, video chat, and payments.
- developed back end (data modeling, authentication, payment processing).

HTML, CSS, React/Redux, MongoDB, Node, Express, JSON Web Tokens, Passport, Socket.io, geolocation API/Google maps, react-stripe-checkout, WebRTC

### **EDUCATION**

BA in History | La Sorbonne, Paris, France Software Engineering Program | Thinkful, New York, NY



# **Yohann Potico**

Software Engineer Brooklyn, NY

e: yohann.potico@gmail.com c: +1 646-427-1670 GitHub: vh2n

## **Programming Languages:**

JavaScript/TypeScript
Python
R
SQL

### Frameworks/Libraries:

React/React Native
Redux
Node.js
GraphQL
ChartJS, D3
Django
Pytorch, Pandas, Numpy
Quantmod

#### **Databases:**

MongoDB Postgres Redis

### **Testing:**

Mocha Chai Jest/RTL

#### **Tools:**

Travis CI, Jenkins
Heroku, Vercel, Netlify
AWS, GCP
TailwindCSS, Chakra UI
Socket.io
WebRTC
Webpack

### Languages:

English French